Vishwa Jayaneththi

heshanjayaneththi96@gmail.com | (+94)71 412 2477 | www.linkedin.com/in/vishwa- jayaneththi-23a9605hv | https://github.com/vish2396

Profile

I am a dedicated and curious Software developer with a profound enthusiasm for open source, cloud, cybersecurity and blockchain technologies. My journey as an open source enthusiast involves relentless exploration and experimentation with a diverse array of technologies and tools, all aimed at continuously enhancing my expertise.

Experience

Blockchain developer intern Bluechip Technologies Asia Pvt Ltd April 2023 – Present Colombo, Sri Lanka

- Developing Decentralized web applications for exact blockchain networks.
- React JS, Node JS, HTML/CSS, JS use for developing web applications.
- Solidity, Rust is used for developing smart contracts.
- Truffle, Hardhat frameworks used for deploying and testing smart contracts.

Trainee Computer Hardware Technician

July 2018 – January 2019

Colombo, Sri Lanka

Mathugama, Sri Lanka

- Metropolitan Computers Pvt Ltd
 - Troubleshooting and Diagnosing Computer and Laptop hardware failures.
 - Troubleshooting and Diagnosing Operating system and software failures.
 - Repairing Hardware and Software failures and errors.
 - Report writing and Customer handling.

Education

Bachelor's degree Computer studies, Physics, Electronics	2019 – 2023
University of Kelaniya	Kelaniya, Sri Lanka
Diploma Network Administration	2018 – 2019
Lalith Athulathmudali Vocational Training College	Rathmalana, Sri Lanaka
NVQ L04 Computer Hardware Technician Department of Technical Education and Training	2018 – 2019 Kalutara, Sri Lanka
Advanced Level Mathematics Stream	2015 – 2017

Certificates

- Information Technology | Advanced Networking
- CISCO Netacad | Coursera

Ananda Sastralaya National School

- Coding & Web Development | Arduino and Robotics | AI & ML Program

Projects

Student Information System – Group Project Using C Programming language

Travel Website – Group Project Using HTML, CSS, JS and PHP, MySQL

Home Automation System – Group Project Using Arduino Microcontroller, Sensors, C Programming language, BLYNK app

Smart Water Irrigation system – Group Project
Using NodeMCU microcontroller, Sensors, Python and C Programming language, MySQL, Microsoft
Azure, Power BI

Personal and Technical Skills

Technical Skills

- Languages & Frameworks: C, JavaScript, Python, Solidity, Rust, React, Node Js, Hardhat, Truffle
- Tools & Technologies: Git/GitHub, Virtualization, Cloud (Azure, AWS, GCloud, IBM), Linux, Cybersecurity, Blockchain.

Personal Skills

- Passion for technology and for building something useful for people, Adaptability, Problem solving, Analytical thinking, Leadership, Continuous Learning.

References

Dr. J. A. Seneviratne | Senior Lecture | University of Kelaniya

Phone: (+94)71 822 6117 Email: jehans@kln.ac.lk

Mr. Prasanga Fernando | Assistant Engineer | Metropolitan Computers Pvt Ltd

Phone: (+94)77 267 4500

Email: prasangaf@metropolitan.lk